<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ward&amp;Westminster</title><link>https://wardwestminster.com/</link><description>Recent content on Ward&amp;Westminster</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wardwestminster.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Child at Mar-a-Lago</title><link>https://wardwestminster.com/2025/12/the-child-at-mar-a-lago/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wardwestminster.com/2025/12/the-child-at-mar-a-lago/</guid><description>&lt;p>Jeffrey Epstein took a 14-year-old girl to Mar-a-Lago in 1994 and introduced her to Donald Trump, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/live-updates/epstein-files-released-2025/">newly released court document&lt;/a> in the first tranche of the so-called &amp;ldquo;Epstein files&amp;rdquo;. The account, buried in hundreds of pages of material disclosed by the US Department of Justice under a new transparency law, adds a disturbing new detail to the long-scrutinised relationship between the late financier and the man who is now president of the United States.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Architecture of Silence</title><link>https://wardwestminster.com/2025/12/the-architecture-of-silence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wardwestminster.com/2025/12/the-architecture-of-silence/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is a particular kind of architecture that exists not in steel and glass but in silence. It is built from omissions, from the careful structuring of who may speak and who must listen, from the deliberate absence of windows where windows ought to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-geography-of-looking-away">The geography of looking away&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Every healthcare institution that has harboured avoidable harm shares certain features. Not the obvious ones — the understaffing, the budget pressures, the asymmetries of power — but something subtler: a grammar of acceptable speech that makes certain truths unsayable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Algorithm Will See You Now</title><link>https://wardwestminster.com/2025/12/the-algorithm-will-see-you-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wardwestminster.com/2025/12/the-algorithm-will-see-you-now/</guid><description>&lt;p>The software makes a recommendation. The doctor reviews it, or doesn&amp;rsquo;t. The patient never knows an algorithm was involved. This is the quiet revolution reshaping clinical medicine.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-economy-of-prediction">The economy of prediction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We have built an entire economy around clinical prediction. Startups promise to catch cancers earlier, flag deteriorating patients sooner, identify drug interactions faster. The pitch decks are compelling. The evidence base is thinner than the marketing suggests.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>AI in healthcare is often framed as augmentation. But there is nothing augmenting about a system that shapes decisions without accountability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Paper Trail</title><link>https://wardwestminster.com/2025/12/the-paper-trail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wardwestminster.com/2025/12/the-paper-trail/</guid><description>&lt;p>The response arrives after 47 days. Inside: 23 pages, 18 of them heavily redacted. Somewhere in this stack of paper lies an answer. Finding it will take months — and several appeals.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-archaeology-of-bureaucracy">The archaeology of bureaucracy&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Healthcare journalism often imagines dramatic confrontations, hidden cameras, sources meeting in underground car parks. The reality is more often this: a desk, a highlighter, and an endless stream of documents obtained through Freedom of Information requests.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://wardwestminster.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wardwestminster.com/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Matt Kneale is an emergency medicine clinical fellow and Co-chair of the &lt;a href="https://dauk.org">Doctors&amp;rsquo; Association UK (DAUK)&lt;/a>, a grassroots organisation representing and defending doctors across the United Kingdom. He has been a passionate advocate for doctors&amp;rsquo; rights and patient safety since joining DAUK in March 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="advocacy--leadership">Advocacy &amp;amp; Leadership&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As Co-chair, Matt works to address critical issues facing the NHS workforce, including chronic understaffing, doctor burnout, and the erosion of professional standards. He has been a vocal critic of policies that compromise patient safety, from inadequate staffing levels to the unregulated expansion of physician associate roles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dr Matt Kneale</title><link>https://wardwestminster.com/authors/dr-matt-kneale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wardwestminster.com/authors/dr-matt-kneale/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://wardwestminster.com/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wardwestminster.com/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>